<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NodeConf EU Badge</title>
    <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on NodeConf EU Badge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 09:45:33 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://nodeconfeubadge.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Connected</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/get-connected/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 09:45:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/get-connected/</guid>
      <description>The first step is going to be getting set up and connected to your badge. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, check out http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/ as a getting started guide.
If you&amp;rsquo;re not on a Mac, you might want to check out Puck.js&amp;rsquo;s guide for setting up the Web IDE: http://www.espruino.com/Puck.js+Quick+Start#using-the-espruino-ide
You should now have a REPL that you can type stuff at!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World on screen</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/hello-world-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/hello-world-screen/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 1 This challenge is just to get you warmed up and comfortable using the Web IDE. See if you can display &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; on the badge&amp;rsquo;s screen.
Check out the Espruino site to see what you can do with Graphics and Fonts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Your Badge</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/unlocking-your-badge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 15:30:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/unlocking-your-badge/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more to your badge&amp;rsquo;s software than you realise. Try this:
 Up Up Down Down Left Right Left Right B A  (Yup the Konami code!)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Slate</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/clean-slate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 09:45:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/clean-slate/</guid>
      <description>Clear everything out of the right-hand side of the IDE window, and click the &amp;lsquo;Upload&amp;rsquo; button in the middle of the screen (a picture of a chip and an up-arrow).
The Badge should now just display the &amp;lsquo;Espruino&amp;rsquo; logo - this is what gets displayed when no code has been loaded.
Don&amp;rsquo;t worry though - this hasn&amp;rsquo;t overwritten what was on the badge before. That code is in Flash memory, and uploading an empty file has left the contents of RAM empty, while the Flash memory has stayed the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Software</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/built-in-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 15:30:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/built-in-software/</guid>
      <description>Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve unlocked the badge (you&amp;rsquo;ll have to do this any time you remove the battery), you can explore the built in sample apps. Out of the box, your badge has the following:
 Your name pre-flashed into the firmware Image display cycling Selectable menus T-Rex who has escaped the Chrome browser Flappy Bird The world&amp;rsquo;s most awkward on-board REPL Etch-a-sketch  Source code for all of these is of course in the Github Repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detect Button Press</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/detect-button-press/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/detect-button-press/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 2 Reading the instantaneous value of a button is easy (see the getting started docs) but how do you deal with debouncing so it&amp;rsquo;s reliable?
What about more than one button being pressed at the same time?
Help is at hand on the Espruino site.
Buttons are a great example of how you write event-driven code with Espruino rather than the more traditional read-loops that people starting on Arduino tend to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capacitive Sense</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/capacitive-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 09:45:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/capacitive-sense/</guid>
      <description>To detect a press, we want to use the capacitive sense functionality on the badge. Type Badge.capSense(1) on the left-hand side of the IDE. You can use tab-complete to help you. You should get a number displayed in the region of about 10,000 - this value depends on the capacitance on that corner of the badge.
Press your finger on the corner marked 1 and try again (up arrow, then enter) - you should see a much higher value - probably over 100,000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detect Capacitive Touch</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/detect-capacitive-touch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/detect-capacitive-touch/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 3 It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to read a capacitance value from the 6 lanyard holes in the badge. Experiment with the code and how the badge responds to touch. Then come up with a use for it.
See the getting started area for the relevant API call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphics</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 09:45:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/graphics/</guid>
      <description>The badge exposes the LCD via a built-in variable called g. This has a bunch of methods such as drawLine or drawString that can be accessed (http://www.espruino.com/Graphics) however each command acts on an internal memory buffer. To update the display itself you need to call g.flip().
Try entering the following code on the left-hand side:
g.clear(); g.drawString(&amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;); g.flip();  The badge should now display the obvious &amp;lsquo;Hello World&amp;rsquo;!
But what if we want to display our capacitance data?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flash LEDs</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/flash-leds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/flash-leds/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 4 It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to add LEDs to the 6 corners of your badge. In fact you probably don&amp;rsquo;t even have to solder them. Just stick them in with the short leg oriented to the squared off side of each white circle.
Then try turning them on and off (hint: check the getting started pages). How about some timer-based patterns too? Or controlling them with the buttons?
Note: The low-power nature of the badge means that if you light all LEDs together they&amp;rsquo;ll be quite dim and you&amp;rsquo;ll burn through the battery much more quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 09:45:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/sound/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;d be nice if our game made some sounds. There&amp;rsquo;s no speaker built into the badge, so we&amp;rsquo;re going to add one.
Get one of the gold coloured discs from the hacking bench - these are piezo speakers of the type you&amp;rsquo;d find in digital watches.
Use the wire strippers and try and strip around 2cm of insulation off each of the two wires. By careful - maybe try stripping 1cm first, then another cm, as the wire is really delicate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting to the Badge</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/connecting-to-the-badge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 15:30:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/connecting-to-the-badge/</guid>
      <description>Any modern computer with Bluetooth 4+ should be able to connect to the badge as follows:
Make your badge connectable  Enter the Konami code, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already: Up, Up, Down, Down, Left, Right, Left, Right, B, A. Select &amp;ldquo;Make badge connectable&amp;rdquo; in the menu Note the Badge ID  Mac Web Bluetooth on Chrome should just work if your Chrome is up to date. So simply go to the Web IDE here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Play Music with Buzzer</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/play-music-with-buzzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/play-music-with-buzzer/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 5 We have lots of buzzers at the Hacking Station. You just have to solder the red wire to one of the D0-D6 holes on the edge of the badge and the black wire to one of the Ground (-) holes.
Then impress everyone with your groovy tunes using the APIs here.
Note: Gordon is working on a variation of this that uses two digital pins and doubles the output volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Game</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/making-a-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 09:45:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/making-a-game/</guid>
      <description>Ok, now we&amp;rsquo;ll need to make two functions:
 A function to output a pattern A function to check the player&amp;rsquo;s input against a pattern.  These will take a simple array of numbers, which is the pattern to output.
Left -&amp;gt; Right We&amp;rsquo;ve got enough code that we probably want to start using the right-hand side of the IDE as a proper editor. No changes will take effect until you press the Upload button, but when you upload it&amp;rsquo;ll blow away any previous changes you made on the left-hand side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World on the Console</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/hello-world-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 15:30:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/hello-world-console/</guid>
      <description>Of course we start with Hello World. Follow the connection instructions, then click on the left hand side of the IDE and type:
console.log(&amp;quot;Hello World&amp;quot;);  Now stop and think for a minute about what just happened there in terms of communications flow.
You should try out other aspects of the Web IDE. It has full auto-complete in the REPL window including Button/LED names and functions.
You could also try the built-in Blockly graphical editor which is very similar to Scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On-Screen Menu</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/on-screen-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/on-screen-menu/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 6 If you implement an on-screen menu with up-down-left-right-select then you could have lots of your challenges on the badge at the same time and demo them to people. Have a look at the github repo for the sample code.
Add to the existing menu You can also try the following:
 Turn off &amp;lsquo;Reset Before Send&amp;rsquo; in the Web IDE options Write your code a bit like this:  Badge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other Code Samples</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/other-code-samples/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 15:30:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/other-code-samples/</guid>
      <description>There are three places you can find code to learn from and use:
 The Badge repo The main Espruino site The Puck.js area of the Espruino site  Badge Repo Code The pre-installed main.js code is a treasure trove of useful snippets. Note however that it&amp;rsquo;s too big to be uploaded in its entirety via the Web IDE.
 Pre-installed badge code  Games Relive your original Gameboy, Nokia and video arcade days with the following games :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broadcast NFC URL</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/broadcast-nfc-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/broadcast-nfc-url/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 7 This is an easy one. Change the NFC URL that your badge transmits. Find someone with a Samsung Galaxy or similar phone to test it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing Hardware Features</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/accessing-hardware-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 15:30:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/accessing-hardware-features/</guid>
      <description>This is an Open Source Hardware project. Schematics and board design files are available in the /hardware directory of the repo.
The badge uses the same core module as the Puck.js and can run most of the same software.
Hardware Features include:
 nRF52832 SoC - 64MHz ARM Cortex M4, 64kB RAM, 512kB Flash, running the Espruino stack Bluetooth Low Energy Powered by a CR2032 battery which can last up to a week depending on what code you are running Daylight-readable LCD screen 6 input buttons Capacitive touch sensors on all 6 corners Digital I/O on all 6 corners Analogue-in on 3 corners Prototyping area with 8 CPU pins accessible Digital I/O on all 8 pins Analogue-in on 4 pins Holes for LEDs on all 6 corners NFC antenna SWD programming pins  Proto holes and corner holes You write or read a digital high/low to/from a hole with:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broadcast Beacons</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/broadcast-beacons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/broadcast-beacons/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 8 Broadcast a URL over Bluetooth LE using Eddystone and/or iBeacon and pick it up on your phone (Android for Eddystone, iPhone for iBeacon).
You&amp;rsquo;ll get lots of guidance on the Puck.js site here for Eddystone and here for iBeacon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What next?</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/what-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 09:45:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/what-next/</guid>
      <description>What about:
 Putting LEDs around the corners and using those to show the correct patterns. However, due to the way the capacitive sense and LEDs are shared, you&amp;rsquo;ll only be able to use White and Blue LEDs, not any of the coloured ones! Getting rid of all the callbacks. I&amp;rsquo;ve been super lazy - you could probably tidy things up a lot more using Promises. Make a much better game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the prototyping area and corners</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/using-prototyping-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 15:30:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/getting-started/using-prototyping-area/</guid>
      <description>You can add whatever hardware you like to the prototyping area. It&amp;rsquo;s where you&amp;rsquo;ll be connecting extra LEDs, buzzers etc. The column of holes along the board&amp;rsquo;s left edge are connected to pins D0 to D8, Ground and Power. However all of the other holes in that grid are unconnected and can be used to attach your components together.
As always, the Espruino web-site has lots more info and examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Noble on Laptop</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/use-noble-on-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/use-noble-on-laptop/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 9 Use the Node.js Bluetooth library Noble on your laptop to read the beacon data that you are transmitting from the earlier challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding to your Badge&#39;s menu</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/adding-to-the-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 09:45:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/workshop/adding-to-the-menu/</guid>
      <description>Next we&amp;rsquo;re going to add the game we just made as a menu item inside the existing badge software.
Wrap everything you&amp;rsquo;ve done into the following function on the right-hand side of the IDE.
Badge.apps[&amp;quot;Simon Game&amp;quot;] = function() { Badge.reset(); setWatch(Badge.menu, BTNB, { repeat: 1, debounce: 50, edge: &amp;quot;rising&amp;quot; }); // Your code };  Now we need to get the badge back doing badgey stuff. disconnect the IDE from your badge, and pull the battery gently away from the PCB with a fingernail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use the Badge as a HID Button</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/use-badge-for-hid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/use-badge-for-hid/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 10 HID means Human Interface Device and it&amp;rsquo;s a standard for connecting Bluetooth input devices like keyboards and mice to computers. Your badge can act as a HID button for your laptop including multimedia keys. You could even use it as a clicker for your talk at NodeConf!
Check out the instructions here and try it out for yourself.
Note: Bluetooth HID can&amp;rsquo;t be enabled on an active connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Display an Image</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/display-an-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/display-an-image/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 11 You can see that we took all of your names and turned them into images that were included as part of the software of each badge. A different image for every badge. Your challenge is to do something similar. Find an image somewhere, convert it into the correct format and display it on the badge. You&amp;rsquo;ll have lots of fun with Imagemagick outputting blank images or inverted ones :-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a Web Bluetooth Page</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/create-web-bluetooth-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/create-web-bluetooth-page/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 12 Implement a webpage that uses Web Bluetooth with the Puck.js library. Start simple and turn on/off an LED on your badge.
Eventually make it retrieve your last tweet from the Twitter API and then display it on the badge screen.
Lots of information about web Bluetooth and Espruino here.
Add a menu via Web Bluetooth You can really see the power of Web Bluetooth and Espruino by trying something like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detect movement with a PIR Sensor</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/detect-person-with-pir-sensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/detect-person-with-pir-sensor/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 13 We have a small number of PIR sensors at the Hacking Table. You can easily wire one of them up to your badge so it can detect motion. Now think of ways you could use that at an event.
You can get started with the code here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect to BLE Lightbulb</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/connect-to-ble-lightbulb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/connect-to-ble-lightbulb/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 14 See if you can connect the Badge to the BLE Lightbulb on the table in the hacking lounge and change its colours.
This is an advanced task and may involve installing the lightbulb&amp;rsquo;s mobile app and using the Nordic Semiconductor mobile apps to read changes in the parameters on the lightbulb.
You can get guidance here and here but they may not contain a solution specific to this lightbulb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect to BLE LED Strip</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/connect-to-ble-led-strip/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/connect-to-ble-led-strip/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 15 See if you can connect the Badge to the BLE LED Strip on the table in the hacking lounge and change its colours.
This is a very advanced task and may involve installing the LED strip&amp;rsquo;s mobile app and using the Nordic Semiconductor mobile apps to read changes in the parameters on the strip.
You can get guidance here and here but they do not contain a solution specific to this strip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicate with another Badge</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/communicate-with-another-badge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/communicate-with-another-badge/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 16 This is another advanced challenge. We recommend starting with the instructions here and then decide if you want to continue.
Also consider the new BLE mesh networking standard which is currently not supported on Espruino but would make for an impressive community contribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicate with another Device</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/communicate-with-other-ble-device/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/communicate-with-other-ble-device/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 17 If you can get your hands on some other BLE device like a Garmin, Fitbit or Milestone, see if you can figure out the protocol.
If you figure it out, write a blogpost about it!
Some of these devices may require registering on the relevant developer sites. However we may have some other Bluetooth devices on the Hacking Table which are easier to communicate with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement Dat Protocol</title>
      <link>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/implement-dat-protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:29:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nodeconfeubadge.org/challenges/implement-dat-protocol/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 18 We&amp;rsquo;re kidding.
Or are we?
What sort of P2P messaging system could be created by all the badges at the event? Without burning through the battery in 5 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>